# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hi everyone, I'm Wang Gang
# 有很多粉丝跟我留言
Many fans have left their comments
# 然后问了一些问题
and asked some questions
# 今天拍这个视频跟大家解释一下
Today I'm shooting this video to explain to you guys
# 这一套炉具相关的一些东西
something about this cooking stove
# 第一个粉丝问这个设备买下来多少钱
One fan asked me how much does this whole set of cooking system take?
# 关于这个的话我后面来跟大家算一个总账多少钱
I'll calculate how much it costs in total later in this video
# 然后第二个是说
Another fan said that
# 让我报个价让他死心
he wanted me to tell the price just to let him give up
# 等一下也放到后面来聊
I'll talk about this later
# 还有一个粉丝就是说这个无论是酒店专用还是怎么样
Another fan said that, no matter in the restaurant or at home
# 他个人认为还是电磁炉实用成本低
He thinks induction cooker is cheaper and more practical
# 这个确实是电磁炉比较实用体积又小
Indeed, induction cooker is easy to use and small
# 拿着就走
You can even bring it with you
# 但是说仅限于是家庭使用或者是单身人士使用
But it's limited to family use, or those who live alone
# 是吧 随拿随走
Right? It's quite portable
# 如果说让我们专业人士来做的话
However, in the case of professional use
# 我至今从来没有用电磁炉炒过菜
I've never cooked any dish with induction cooker
# 电磁炉在我们(后厨)迫不得已的话我只用它来煮一些汤
In restaurant kitchens, we only use induction cookers to make soup if there is no other choice
# 或者是炖一些菜
Or stew some food
# 从来不会用它做炒菜
But we never use induction cookers to make stir-fry dishes
# 因为你一炒的话
Because if you stir-fry food with it
# 刚开始锅热的时候还行
It's OK in the beginning when the wok is still hot
# 菜一下去一会儿这个东西就是叫做煮菜不叫做炒菜
However when you put more food into the wok, it turns into "boiling" instead of "stir-frying"
# 好啦现在我来介绍一下这边
Alright. Let me introduce this now
# 这个报价就是粉丝最关心的一个问题留言最多的一个问题
Most fans are really concerned about the price. That's the most frequently asked question too.
# 也好让你们死一下心
Let me tell you so that you can give up
# 这一个你们看得到的这个
This one, as you can see
# 不锈钢的叫做打荷台
This table made of stainless steel is called "Da He Tai" (Spreader table)
# 这个打荷台有贵有便宜
Well, its price can vary
# 它贵与便宜区别在于皮有厚有薄
depending on how thick the steel "skin" is #请检查这里，我在这里用了skin表示外皮，但是后面用了sheet，算是铁皮的通用说法，不知道这样是否合适
# 最薄的是0.4毫米
The thinnest sheet can be 0.4 mm
# 然后有0.6毫米
While some are 0.6 mm
# 有1.0毫米
and 1.0 mm
# 一般来说0.4毫米的话就300多块钱一张
Generally a "Da He Tai" with 0.4 mm thick sheet is about 300 yuan
# 这个它宽度是80（厘米）长是1.8（米）高度也是80（厘米）
The dimensions of this table are 80 cm in width and height, while 1.8 m in length
# 然后它这个便宜的话用手可以按进去
For the cheapest ones, if you press it with your hand
# 可以这样用力按就是一个窝
there'll be a dent on it
# 所以这个质量就非常差
In that case, the quality is really bad
# 然后我买得这款是0.6毫米的
This one that I bought is with 0.6 mm-thick sheet
# 这个中间加了木板
With a wooden board sandwiched in the middle
# 然后普通家庭用的话还是非常不错
It's pretty ideal for family use
# 如果是我们专业厨房的话
But in a professional kitchen
# 最好用1.0（毫米）以上的
It's better to use the table with a sheet thickness over 1.0 mm
# 因为1.0以上的我们
Because for those tables (with sheets thicker than 1.0 mm)
# 剁菜的时候一刀剁下去或者是说用力捶一下一点不会变形
when you chop the food, or hit it hard, the table won't deform
# 质量非常的好 但是它非常贵
It's of high quality, but very expensive
# 0.6（毫米）的是900多
The table with 0.6 mm-thick skin is more than 900 yuan
# 然后1.0以上的还要分中间有没有这个隔层
For those with sheet over 1.0 mm thick, the price also depends on if there are shelving racks
# 有没有拉门
and sliding doors
# 就是最便宜的没有拉门两层的是1600块钱左右
The cheapest two-layer table without sliding door is about 1,600 yuan
# 如果有拉门有隔层的最少2000块钱以上
If it's with sliding doors and shelving racks, it will be at least 2,000 yuan
# 我们厨房里面就拿一个灶来说
Typically in a professional kitchen, for each cooking stove
# 最少配两张
It should be accompanied with at least two tables
# 所以这里的话两张我们就按照最贵的来算3000多
So here we've got two tables, assuming they are the most expensive ones, it would be more than 3,000 yuan
# 3800块钱
3,800 yuan
# 然后我买这两个的话花了1960块钱
For these two, I spent 1,960 yuan
# 两张花了1960块钱
1,960 yuan for these two tables
# 然后第二件东西的话就是这个菜板砧板这一块
The second thing is the cutting board
# 这个砧板的话你看有这么厚
You see, this cutting board is so thick
# 10-20公分厚
about 10-20 cm thick
# 这块的话就不贵
This one is not expensive though
# 但是非常的笨重
But very bulky and heavy
# 有50-60斤
It's about 50-60 Jin (25-30 kg)
# 然后120块钱左右吧
And it's about 120 yuan
# 这个东西是不贵
Well, it's not expensive indeed
# 应该说整个厨房当中是比较便宜的一个东西
It should be one of the cheapest things in kitchen
# 然后就是菜刀
Next, the cleaver #还是kitchen knife?
# 菜刀就不用说了家庭用的话就随便
Well, it doesn't matter what kind of cleaver you use in family kitchen
# 有的粉丝说5块钱也可以买一把
Some fans say you can buy one for 5 yuan
# 但是我们这个如果要用得好一点
However, if you want to use a better one
# 质量OK的话最少100块钱以上
You need to spend at least 100 yuan for a high quality cleaver
# 然后品牌的话就自己去选
Choose the brand on your own
# 现在我来说一下这个最主要的东西就是这个炉灶
Now I'm gonna talk about the most important thing, the cooking stove
# 这个炉灶的话我是按照顶配来买的
This stove I bought is with the best configurations
# 它的价格是3800块钱左右
It's about 3,800 yuan
# 如果你想配置更高一点
If you want even better configurations
# 加两个鼓风机
For example, with two blowers
# 要加钱
You need to pay extra money
# 大概要加1000块钱
That's about 1,000 yuan
# 然后就是4800左右 再配上一个运费
So that's about 4,800 yuan in total, excluding the delivery charge
# 因为经销商它不会给你包邮的
Since the seller usually doesn't include the delivery charge in the price
# 因为他给你拉过来什么的都是要钱
as he must deliver it to you, which costs some money
# 加运费这一坨
With the delivery charge included...
# 我是成都买的 到我们这个地方
I bought this from Chengdu. To deliver it here,
# 花了800多块钱的运费
I spent about 800 yuan just for delivery
# 不是说你这些买回来就可以用
In addition, actually you can't use them immediately even if you have all these stuff
# 第一你如果是接煤气的话你要买煤气罐 对吧
For example, if you wanna use LPG, you'll also need to buy gas tanks
# 如果你是用天然气的话你要开户
Or, if you want to use natural gas, you need to sign a contract with some company
# 开户的话这个多少钱我就不知道了
I don't know how much that'll cost
# 然后就是可以烧环保油
You can also use eco-friendly oil instead
# 这三种无非就是怎么样转换呢
It's not hard to switch between different fuels
# 把炉心根据你用什么燃料然后就换什么炉心 很简单比较便宜
You can replace the stove core according to the type of fuel. It's simple and cheap
# 这是第一个气就是燃料这一块
This is the first issue. The fuel
# 第二的话就是电
Secondly, you need to have electricity supply
# 你知道这个有鼓风机对吧
You know, there's a blower
# 这个要拉线来接上这个鼓风机
You'll need (to buy) cables for the blower
# 它还要耗电
It consumes electricity as well
# 有了电和气还不行
Electricity and fuel supply are still not enough though
# 还要接上水
Water is also needed
# 因为这个炉的话温度比较高
Because the temperature of this stove is relatively high
# 你如果不放水这里两下就烧坏了
If there's no water here, it'll be burnt easily
# 要接上水
So you need to connect water supply as well
# 还有一个最重要的一个点
Moreover, the most important point
# 油烟机
The range hood
# 如果你的楼房特别高
Suppose your building is very tall
# 你要从一楼装一个排烟道装到楼顶
and you'll need an exhaust duct from the first floor to the roof
# 那这个（费用）可多可少
The price can be very high #请检查这里，按照前面的说法应该是比较高的
# 我做过的餐厅最贵的装一根油烟管道花了10万
In one of the restaurants that I worked in, they spent 100,000 yuan on installing an exhaust duct pipe
# 如果你是在自己家里面
If you want to have it in your home
# 就是农村的家你不能在城市里面
In the countryside, of course, not in the city
# 城市里面你很难弄进去
It's very hard to install this in your home in the city
# 然后也会非常吵
It'll also be very noisy
# 在自己家里面的话这一套下来
In your home... If you really want to have a whole set of these equipments
# 全部置办下来到你能够炒菜
In total, I mean, when you can really start cooking
# 我估计的话预算 大概预算是1万块钱
I think the budget will be approximately 10,000 yuan
# 然后我建不建议你们这么做呢
And... what do I suggest?
# 其实不建议你们这么做
In fact I don't suggest you to do so (have such a set in your home)
# 第一是价钱让你们死心
First, the price is high enough to let you give up
# 第二是这个操作也是让你们死心
Second, the operations are also very complicated #请检查这里，不太按照原文
# 然后最后一点呢
And at last,
# 你这些东西买回来了之后
even if you have all these
# 你不会用也是很麻烦的你看
It'll be a trouble if you can't use them
# 随便一个你炒菜必须用这个锅 家用的锅放不进去
For example, you must use this wok when cooking. The woks for family cooking cannot be used here
# 因为这个特别大
Also, since it's really big
# 放进去了之后你不可能用锅铲这样子炒
You can't use a spatula and cook as usual
# 而你要配上这一套技术对吧
You'll need cooking skills like this
# 你不可能买了这一套东西然后花个10年8年去学烹饪什么的
It's not practical that you buy such a set of equipments and spend 10 or 8 years on learning how to cook professionally
# 这个也不大现实
It's not realistic
# 所以我们大家对于说买这套炉具来自己家用的话就看一下就好啦
So for you guys, it's not recommended that you buy all these for family use
# 如果你们实在是想
If you really want to...
# 还想买的话我就建议你们
to have these in your home, I would suggest you
# 其实不用买双灶
You don't actually need a dual-stove cooker
# 有单灶的 单灶就便宜很多
There's single-stove cooker. It's much cheaper
# 第一呢它运费便宜
First, the delivery fee is rather low
# 第二呢它是买得也便宜
Second, it's cheap as well
# 单灶的话1000多块钱
For a single-stove cooker, it's about 1,000 yuan
# 它也带鼓风机
It's also with a blower
# 然后的话它面积就比这个小很多很多
It occupies much less area than this one
# 就更方便于操作
So it's easy to operate
# 我们买得这一套是中配
This set here is middle-end
# 如果你想买简约一点的可以买一个小的
You can buy a small one instead
# 先尝试一下能不能驾驭得了这个
and try if you can handle it
# 如果能驾驭得了我们以后再慢慢扩也可以
If you do, you can upgrade it gradually in the future
# 就是说烹饪作为一个爱好
I mean, if cooking is your hobby
# 我们这一套全部按照最顶格来配的话
For this set here, if all with the best configurations
# 不考虑油烟机大概2万块钱左右
In total it'll be about 20,000 yuan, excluding the range hood
# 就相当于翻了一番价格
That is, twice the price now
# 如果按照最简约的来配的话
If with the simplest configurations
# 打荷台300多
300 yuan for the spreading table
# 然后这个炉灶带鼓风机的单个炉灶1000多
and about 1,000 yuan for a single-stove cooker with a blower
# 加上菜板什么的
as well as the cutting board, etc.
# 所有加起来2000块钱以内
All add up below 2,000 yuan
# 都是OK的
That's also OK
# 然后也有粉丝再问
Some fans also asked
# 他说你买这一套来干什么呢
why I bought this set here
# 其实我买这一套炉具来
Actually I buy them
# 第一是跟大家分享它的作用
because I want to share with you how it works
# 可能大家没看过真正后厨的这个是怎么样子操作
Maybe you guys have never seen what it's like in real restaurant kitchens
# 然后呢也是从第一步炒菜跟大家分享
Also, I want to share with you from the first step of cooking
# 从翻锅开始到后面的我会的
From flipping food in the wok, to whatever I can
# 跟你们分享
I'll share with you
# 这就是我买这一套厨具的初衷
That's why I bought this set of equipments
# 好啦本期视频就到这里结束
Ok that's the end of this video
# 喜欢我的可以关注一下我
If you like my videos, please subscribe
# 后面慢慢来 我们来日方长慢慢得学
I'll share with you in the future. We still have a lot of time to learn
# 我也在不断的学习
I'm also learning continuously
# 跟大家分享更多的东西
and I'll share more with you
# 好啦 就到这里
Ok. That's the end
# 拜拜
Bye-bye!